Register of the Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1988 (Boxes 105-141)
  - Mountbatten, Louis. Speech, clippings, and correspondence with Ronald Brockman, Jimmy Carter, Barbara Cartland, Henry Leach, Terence Lewin, Philip Ziegler and others, 1947-1985 (Box-folder 120: 5)
  - National Association for Uniformed Services. Articles of incorporation, newsletter, pamphlet, and correspondence with T. G. W. Settle and others, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 121: 1)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences. By-laws, letters, and miscellany, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 121: 2)
  - Nebraska. Pamphlets, serial issues, clippings, leaflets, miscellany, and correspondence with Robert Dobson, Norbert T. Tiemann and others, 1956-1989 (Box-folder 121: 3)
  - Nebraska Society. Newsletters, miscellany, and correspondence with Charles Thone and others, 1968-1989 (Box-folder 121: 4)
  - Nixon, Richard. Correspondence and clipping, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 121: 5)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). Speeches, outline, letters, printed material, and treaty text, 1949-1973 (Box-folder 121: 6)
  - Nuclear weapons and arms control. Reports, clippings, pamphlets, printed articles, statements by J. B Conant, John Foster Dulles, Thomas E. Murray, Paul Nitze, Francis Pym, W. W. Rostow and others, and correspondence with Sidney Drell, Nicholas Henderson, Francis B. Sayre, Jr. and others
    - 1952-1957 (Box-folder 121: 7)
    - 1963-1988 (Box-folder 122: 1)
  - Ochsner, Alton. Reports, speeches by Ochsner, letters, printed material, biographical sketch, and newsletters, 1947-1982 (Box-folder 122: 2)
  - Panama Canal. Clippings, memorandum, statements by John Wayne and others, treaty texts, and correspondence with G. Russell Evans, Wayne and others, 1965-1988 (Box-folder 122: 3)
  - Patton, George. Clippings, typescript of Kent Hunter, "Eight Steps to Glory," and correspondence with Ernie Deane, Ladislas Farago, Frank Mason, Andrew O'Meara, and Mrs. Patton, 1947-1987 (Box-folder 122: 4)
  - "Peking Informers." Bulletins
    - 1968 (Box-folder 122: 5)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 123: 1)
  - Petroleum. Mimeograph copy of "Strategic Oil Supplies," letters by H. L. Hunt, and writings by Hunt and others, 1950-1969 (Box-folder 123: 2)
  - Philippines. Pamphlet, notes, miscellany, and correspondence with Carlos Romulo and others, 1956-1978 (Box-folder 123: 3)
  - Population. Reprint, chart, and letter to Lister Hill, 1949-1967 (Box-folder 123: 4)
  - Psychological warfare, 1944-1963 (Box-folder 123: 5)
    Pamphlet, newsletters, speech by Bonner Fellers, interview transcript with P. M. A. Linebarger, and typescript copies of "Are We Losing the Cold War?" and Paul C. Davis, "Propaganda and American Foreign Policy," mimeograph copies of "Winning the Cold Peace: Soviet Communism and U. S. Psychological Warfare," and "Suggestions on Psychological Warfare," and correspondence with Davis and another.
  - QED (organization). Printed material, notes, miscellany, and correspondence with E. Robert Anderson, William LaVarre, Ronald Reagan, Ivan Yeaton and others, 1965-1987 (Box-folder 123: 6)
  - Race relations. Printed material, 1962-1985 (Box-folder 123: 7)
  - Reagan, Ronald. Clippings, speeches, miscellany, and correspondence with Donald Armstrong, Earl Smith, David Stockman and others, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 123: 8)
  - Religion. Pamphlets and letter, 1955-1973 (Box-folder 123: 9)
  - Republican Party. Miscellany, and correspondence with Earl Smith, Ronald Reagan and others, 1951-1988 (Box-folder 123: 10)
  - Rheem Manufacturing Company. Clipping, memoranda, and correspondence with Richard S. Rheem and others, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 124: 1)
  - Rhodesia. Pamphlets, newsletters, speeches by Ian Smith and another, and correspondence with Claudius Pendill, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 124: 2)
  - Rickenbacker, Edward M. Printed article, leaflet, and clipping, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 124: 3)
  - Robinett, Paul M. Typescript by Robinett (?), "German Participation in the U. S. Army Historical Program," correspondence between Robinett and Dwight D. Eisenhower, and correspondence with H. Maurice Robinett, 1932-1976 (Box-folder 124: 4)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin and Eleanor. Correspondence and printed articles by Eleanor Roosevelt, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 124: 5)
  - Science and medicine. Clippings, flyers, newsletters, printed articles, and correspondence, 1956-1986 (Box-folder 124: 6)
  - Service, John. Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 124: 7)
  - Sokolsky, George. Letter and writings by Sokolsky, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 124: 8)
  - Sorge case. Bulletins, printed article, memoranda, a Japanese report entitled A Partial Documentation of the Sorge Espionage Case, clippings, and notes by Charles A. Willoughby, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 124: 9)
  - Soviet Union
    Newsletters, reports, printed articles, pamphlets (in English and Russian), notes, printed copy of the U.S. Committee on Public Information, The German-Bolshevik Conspiracy, mimeograph copies of John Scott, "The Soviet Economic Offensive," and "The Soviet World," and correspondence with Scott and others.
    - 1918-1963 (Box-folder 124: 10)
    - 1964-1980 (Box-folder 125: 1)
  - Stauffenberg, Claus von. Interview reports, typescript copy of D. J. Hume, "Claus Schenk, Count von Stauffenberg, Traitor or Patriot?" and correspondence with Hume, Peter C. Hoffman, Karl Kracklauer, Joachim Kramarz and others, 1945-1984 (Box-folder 125: 2)
  - Stilwell, Joseph. Clipping and correspondence with John N. Hart, James Lunt, and John Thompson, 1959-1972 (Box-folder 125: 3)
  - Taft, Robert A. Speeches and writings by Taft, minutes, reports, clippings, broadcast transcript, pamphlet, and correspondence with May Davie, I. Jack Martin and others, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 125: 4-5)
    See also: United States-Politics and government/1952 presidential campaign/Taft, Robert A.
    Includes material relating to the Robert A. Taft Memorial Foundation and the Robert A. Taft Institute of Government.
  - Taiwan
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1956-1988 (Box-folder 125: 6)
      - Non-printed material. Meeting memorandum, speeches, notes, biographical sketches, lists, and miscellany
        - Undated (Box-folder 125: 7)
        - 1956-1981 (Box-folder 126: 1)
      - Printed material. Pamphlets, clippings, newsletters, printed articles, serial issues, and speeches, 1956-1988 (Box-folder 126: 2-6)
    - Steel industry. Reports, memoranda, clippings, and correspondence with K. T. Li, Eugene J. Schulte, David Spray and others, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 127: 1)
  - Tibet. Clippings and correspondence with Rosemary Tung, 1980 (Box-folder 127: 2)
    Relates to photographs taken in 1942 during an O.S.S. expedition headed by Ilia Tolstoy.
  - Tolstoy Foundation. Printed material, minutes, reports, biographical sketches, speeches and writings by Alexandra Tolstoy and others, and correspondence with T. K. Bagration, Jimmy Carter, the Dalai Lama, Alexandra Tolstoy, Ilia Tolstoy and others
    - 1951 - 1982 January (Box-folder 127: 3-5)
    - 1982 March - 1985 (Box-folder 128: 1)
  - Townsend Investment Company. Correspondence and miscellany, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 128: 2)
  - Union Chemical and Materials Corporation
    - General. Reports and correspondence with Curtis W. Cannon, J. Edgar Hoover, Byron White and others, 1957-1970 (Box-folder 128: 3)
    - Legal documents
      - 1958-1960 (Box-folder 128: 4-5)
      - 1960-1961 (Box-folder 129: 1)
  - Union Electric Power Corporation. Minutes, financial statements, tax forms, memorandum, and correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 129: 2)
  - United Nations
    - General. Printed material, report, pamphlet by Myron Fagan, serial issues, and letter, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 129: 3)
    - International Court of Justice (World Court). Memoranda, resolution, newsletters, printed material, report, and correspondence with Frank E. Holman and George S. Montgomery, Jr., 1959-1965 (Box-folder 129: 4)
      Relates to the Connolly Amendment regulating the jurisdictional authority of the World Court.
  - United States-Foreign economic relations. Report, pamphlet, letter, printed material, speech, bulletin, and memorandum, 1953-1978 (Box-folder 129: 5)
  - United States-Foreign relations
    - General
      - General, 1945-1988 (Box-folder 130: 1-2)
        Interviews, memoranda, reports, broadcast transcripts, pamphlets, printed articles, clippings, flyers, press release, newsletters, statements by James H. R. Cromwell, Hamilton Fish, Clare Boothe Luce, Maxwell Taylor and others, and correspondence with Mark Hartley, Howard Jones, Gnter Moltmann, and others.
      - Economic assistance, American. Memorandum, clipping, pamphlet, and speech, 1945-1952 (Box-folder 130: 3)
      - Military assistance, American. Speech by Robert A. Lovett, typescript copy of James H. R. Cromwell, "Proposal for an American 'Foreign Legion,'" report, charts, bills, and correspondence with Roderick Stephens and Frank Taylor, 1952-1959 (Box-folder 130: 4)
    - China
      - General
        - General, 1951-1987 (Box-folder 130: 5-7)
          Bulletin, printed articles, newsletters, questionnaires, clippings, reports by Horace Eng and B. F. Taylor, testimony by Harold Stassen, typescript copies of Chin-tung Liang, "Patrick Hurley, The China Mediator," and Tong-Chin Rhee, "A Brief Synopsis of the Sino-American Relations from 1944-1948 Amidst the Internal Conflicts in China," and correspondence with Rhee, Taylor and others.
        - Correspondence, 1955-1987 (Box-folder 131: 1)
      - Wedemeyer Mission, 1950-1985 (Box-folder 131: 2)
        Clippings, mimeograph excerpts, typescript dissertation proposal by John Lee, "Wedemeyer in China: A Study of Sino-American Military and Diplomatic Relations, 1944-1949," mimeograph copy of Chen Hang Hsieh, "General Albert C. Wedemeyer's Mission to China in 1947," and correspondence with Chen, Lee and others.
    - East Asia. Notes, mimeograph copy of Esson M. Gale, "American Dilemma--East Asia or Western Europe?" and printed copy of W. W. Rostow and Richard W. Hatch, An American Policy in Asia, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 131: 3)
    - Soviet Union, 1928-1986 (Box-folder 131: 4-5)
      Printed articles, clippings, notes, pamphlets, speeches by James H. R. Cromwell, Robert Gros, David Sarnoff, James D. Watkins and others, typescript by Chesly Manly, mimeograph Comintern report and resolutions, and a Leadership Foundation report, "Mesmerized by the Bear," and correspondence with Harry F. Byrd, Carl Curtis, James Eastland, Roman L. Hruska, Edward Kennedy, Frank J. Lausche, Charles Percy, John Stennis, Herman Talmadge, and Joseph D. Tydings.
    - Taiwan. Memoranda, clippings, and letter, 1954-1982 (Box-folder 131: 6)
      Primarily relates to American military assistance.
  - United States-History. Broadcast transcript, pamphlets, memoranda, reports, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence with Victor Emanuel, Paul J. Sedgwick and others, 1950-1987 (Box-folder 132: 1)
  - United States-Military
    - General, 1922-1988 (Box-folder 132: 2-4)
      Reports, clippings, organizational guidelines, speech material, statistical charts, printed articles, pamphlets, transcript of testimony by Truman Smith, mimeograph copy of Bradford G. Chynoweth, "The Role of the Military in the United States," and correspondence with Chynoweth, Edward M. Coffman, Arthur A. Ageton, Robert M. Ancell, H. G. Sparrow and others. Includes answers to a questionnaire by Elizabeth Wedemeyer.
    - "Landpower AUSA: Issues Impacting on the Land Forces of the United States," reports, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 132: 5-6)
  - United States-Politics and government
    - General. Pamphlets, memorandum, clippings, speeches, broadcast transcripts, reports, newsletters, and correspondence with Bracken Lee and others, 1947-1984 (Box-folder 133: 1)
    - 1952 presidential campaign
      - General, 1952-1958 (Box-folder 133: 2)
        Broadcast transcripts, clippings, delegate lists, memoranda, platform statements, writings by H. L. Hunt and others, speeches by Herbert Hoover, William F. Knowland, and Felix Morley, and correspondence with Victor Emanuel, Knowland, Douglas MacArthur, Walter Robertson, Earl Schaefer, Robert Welch and others.
      - Taft, Robert A. Statements and speeches by Taft and George Creel, clippings, printed excerpt, correspondence, and miscellany, 1952-1976 (Box-folder 133: 3)
    - 1956 presidential campaign. Newsletters and clippings (Box-folder 133: 4)
    - 1960 presidential campaign. Clippings, leaflet, and correspondence (Box-folder 133: 5)
    - 1964 presidential campaign
      - Goldwater, Barry. Clippings, campaign material, pamphlets, newsletters, speeches, miscellany, and correspondence with Robert Berry, Frank Cullen Brophy, Sherman Chickering, J. B. Condliffe, Perkins McGuire, Dudley Swim and others, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 133: 6)
      - Republican National Convention. Clippings, newsletters, typescript statement, correspondence, and miscellany, 1964 (Box-folder 133: 7)
      - Wallace, George. Clippings and correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 133: 8)
        Relates to the possibility of Wedemeyer joining the Wallace campaign as his vice-presidential running mate.
    - 1976 presidential campaign. Flyer and clipping (Box-folder 133: 9)
      Relates to Gerald Ford.
  - United States. Air Force. Draft legislation, mimeograph copy of John E. Upston, Jr., "Retired United States Air Force Generals: Their Place in Society," and correspondence with Upston and others, 1956-1983 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - United States. Navy. Pamphlets, book reviews, newsletters, reprint, clippings, biographical sketch of Alvin Trexel, and correspondence, 1951-1986 (Box-folder 134: 2)
  - United States Military Academy, circa 1915-1986 (Box-folder 134: 3-4)
    Programs, clippings, report, reprint, miscellany, speech by Douglas MacArthur, booklet by Herbert G. Sparrow, The Times of Our Lives: Story of a West Point Class, booklet, and correspondence with Emmett J. Bean, Andrew J. Goodpaster, Roland McNamee, Richard P. Ovenshine and others. Includes material relating to a 90th birthday tribute to Albert Wedemeyer.
  - Veterans. Report, clippings, letter, circular, speech material, newsletters, pamphlets, and correspondence, 1949-1982 (Box-folder 134: 5)
  - Vietnam, 1954-1985 (Box-folder 134: 6)
    Reports, clippings, newsletters, broadcast transcript, speech by J. W. Fulbright, printed articles, mimeograph copies of Ira Eaker, "The President's Options in Vietnam," and David H. White, "American Soldiers and the Franco-Viet Minh Struggle in Indochina, 1945," and correspondence with Hilaire du Berrier, Edward Drachman, Philip E. Gallagher, Mark Hatfield, Mario Lazo, Carl Neprud, William Douglas Pawley, White and others.
  - Wainwright, Jonathan M. Correspondence with Duane Schultz, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 135: 1)
  - Walker, Edwin. Clippings, draft resolution, and correspondence with Arch E. Roberts and another, 1961 (Box-folder 135: 2)
  - Watergate. Clipping and correspondence with Homer Ferguson and another, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 135: 3)
  - Weapons. Correspondence, printed article, mimeograph copy of an American Security Council report, "The Changing Strategic Military Balance," and clipping, 1962-1982 (Box-folder 135: 4)
  - Wedemeyer University (proposed). Report, proposal, and correspondence with Howard Chen, Wego W. K. Chiang, and B. J. Shell, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 135: 5-6)
    Includes printed material relating to Northrop University.
  - White, Harry Dexter. Interview and letter by J. Anthony Panuch, testimony by J. Edgar Hoover, and printed material, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 135: 7)
    See also: SOUND RECORDINGS.
  - Wood, Leonard. Correspondence with Byron S. Martin, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 135: 8)
  - World War (1939-1945)
    - General
      - Correspondence
        Includes a letter from Franklin Roosevelt to Winston Churchill.
        - 1941-1977 (Box-folder 135: 9)
        - 1979-1986 (Box-folder 136: 1)
      - Non-printed material, 1945-1971 (Box-folder 136: 2)
        Notes, press release, typescript copy of E. van der Vlugt, "Could Eisenhower Lose the War in Europe?" and mimeograph copies of "The Challenges of Victory and Peace," "Memorandum on Ending the Japanese War," and Maurice Matloff, "Strategic Planning for Coalitional Warfare, 1943-1944," and miscellany.
      - Printed material. Clippings, leaflets, pamphlet, and printed articles, 1943-1986 (Box-folder 136: 3-4)
    - Channel invasion. Notes, charts, clippings, and correspondence with Claire Hutchin, P. M. Robinett and others, 1956-1984 (Box-folder 136: 5)
    - China-Burma-India Theater (Box-folder 137: 1-2)
      - Correspondence, 1953-1988
        Includes correspondence with Hanson Baldwin, Robert I. Dodge, Jr., George Fox Mott, R. R. Neyland, and Yasuji Okamura.
      - Non-printed material
        - General. Notes and typescripts by Joseph Elia, Charles K. Parker, and Shen-Yu Dai, 1951-1984 (Box-folder 137: 3)
        - "History of the China Theatre," typescript (incomplete), undated (Box-folder 137: 4)
        - Lee, Orient, "The Second Sino-Japanese War, July 7, 1937-August 14, 1945: A Preliminary Summary," typescript and letter, circa 1980 (Box-folder 137: 5)
        - McReynolds, George B., "China Remembered," typescript, 1985 (Box-folder 138: 1)
        - Romanus, Charles F. and Riley Sunderland, "Time Runs Out in CBI," typescript and correspondence with Paul Caraway, Robert B. McClure, and R. W. Stephens, 1956
          - Part One (Box-folder 138: 2)
          - Part Two (Box-folder 139: 1)
      - Printed material. Clippings, printed excerpt, report, booklet, and cover letter, 1946-1985 (Box-folder 139: 2)
    - German troop dispositions. Questionnaire by General Warlimont, charts, and letters by Horst von Mellenthin, 1956 (Box-folder 139: 3)
    - Victory Plan
      - General. Typescript copy of Stephanie Zach, "The Victory Plan Mystery and the Role of General A. C. Wedemeyer," and correspondence with John Behrens, J. Edgar Hoover, Clarence Kelley, Charles E. Kirkpatrick, Chesly Manly, William French Smith, Strom Thurmond, Walter Trohan, Burton K. Wheeler and others, 1941-1988 (Box-folder 139: 4)
      - Federal Bureau of Investigation report, photocopy
        - Parts 1-2 (Box-folder 140: 1-2)
        - Parts 3-4 (Box-folder 141: 1-2)
  - Young Americans for Freedom. Reports, pamphlets, memoranda, leaflets, and correspondence with William F. Buckley, Douglas Caddy, Charles Edison, George Fox Mott, George Sokolsky and others, 1960-1984 (Box-folder 141: 3-4)
  - Yugoslavia. Correspondence with Thomas P. Murphy, 1957 (Box-folder 141: 5)
    Relates to U.S. aid to Yugoslavia.
- OVERSIZE FILE, [1853], 1920-1983 (Boxes 142-151)
  Scrapbooks, maps, printed material, certificates, awards, diplomas, medals, plaques, and a scroll.
  - Scrapbook of clippings, circa 1942-1945 (Box 142)
  - Bound volume of copies of Stars and Stripes, 1946 January - April (Box 143)
  - Scrapbook of clippings, 1947 (Box 144)
    Relates to the Wedemeyer mission to China.
  - Scrapbook (disassembled), 1949-1951 (Box 145)
  - Scrapbook of clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 146)
    Relates to Wedemeyer Reports!
  - Medals (Boxes 147-148)
  - Plaques (Boxes 149-150)
  - Scrapbook, maps, printed material, certificates, awards, diplomas, scroll, [1853], 1920-1983 (Box 151)
- MAP FILE, 1937-1942 (Map case)
  Two maps, of Germany and Europe.
- MEMORABILIA (On-shelf shelf)
  One scroll, one baton, six swords, two ceremonial keys, one ceramic dish with pigment for a Chinese seal, a blue and white ceramic tea set, a set of silver rice dishes, and one cloisonne bowl.
- PHOTOGRAPHS, circa 1897-1987 (Boxes 153-163)
  Circa 2565 prints / 2 albums, 72 envelopes (in boxes)
  - 1 album (circa 177 prints) of Robert B. McClure commanding troops in China, 1945 (Box 153)
  - 2 albums (circa 165 prints) relating to the Wedemeyers' trip to Taiwan, 1965 October (Box 154)
  - 1 album (circa 15 prints) of a visit to the home of Martin Kuebart in Germany, 1937; 1 album (circa 56 prints) of photographs relating to a trip to Europe by William H. Draper, Jr., circa 1947-1948 (Box 155)
  - 93 prints (12 duplicates) and 1 negative of photographs and portraits of Albert Wedemeyer, 1897-1980s (Box 156, Envelope C-E)
  - 8 sketches, cartoons and caricatures (2 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer, 1944-1951 (Box 156, Envelope F)
  - 44 prints relating to the Wedemeyer family, 1918-1975; 6 prints of the Wedemeyer home, Friends Advice (Box 156, Envelope G)
  - 26 miscellaneous prints, primarily photographs of individuals; 2 scenes of Washington, D.C., undated (Box 156, Envelope H)
  - 77 prints (2 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer and other individuals, including Dwight Eisenhower, Patrick Hurley, Patricia and Louis Mountbatten, and the Duchess of Windsory and others, circa 1940-1959 (Box 156, Envelope I-J)
  - 53 prints (4 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer and other individuals including Chen Cheng, Richard Nixon, Peter Pee, Maxwell Taylor and others, 1960-1968 (Box 156, Envelope K)
  - 77 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and others, including Herbert Hoover, Richard Nixon, Lowel Thomas and others at the Bohemian Grove, circa 1940-1959 (Box 156, Envelope L)
  - 50 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and others, 1971-1979 (Box 156, Envelope M)
  - 75 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and others, including Alexander Haig, 1980-1987 (Box 157, Envelope N)
  - 36 prints of the Wedemeyer's 60th wedding anniversary, 1985 February 5 (Box 157, Envelope O)
  - 33 prints of Albert Wedemeyer's trip to Omaha, Nebraska to receive an award from Alpha Sigma Nu, Creighton University, 1959 (Box 157, Envelope P)
  - 18 prints (2 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer's trip to Texas and California, 1959; 6 prints of his trip to Germany, 1960 (Box 157, Envelope Q)
  - 121 prints (3 duplicates) of Albert and Elizabeth Wedemeyer in Taiwan, visiting military facilities and various individuals [See also: Box 154, Box 163/Envelope mSSS], 1965-1981 (Box 157, Envelope R-S)
  - 10 prints of General and Mrs. Wedemeyer in the Philippines, 1965-1969 (Box 157, Envelope T)
  - 17 prints of Albert Wedemeyer receiving honorary degrees, undated (Box 157, Envelope U)
  - 42 prints and 1 proof sheet of awards presentations and speeches by Albert Wedemeyer, 1955-1985 (Box 157, Envelope V)
    Includes photographs of Ronald Reagan.
  - 39 prints (1 duplicate) of scenes of the U.S. Military Academy, and of Albert Wedemeyer and others at West Point, circa 1917-1973 (Box 158, Envelope W)
  - 34 prints relating to Albert Wedemeyer's early military career, including assignments in Washington, D.C. and the Philippines, undated (Box 158, Envelope X)
    Includes photographs of Calvin Coolidge and Herbert Hoover.
  - 51 scenes of China and of the Wedemeyer family in China, circa 1929-1931 (Box 158, Envelope Y-Z)
  - 16 prints (6 duplicates) of Albert Wedemeyer and military colleagues in Germany, circa 1936-1938 (Box 158, Envelope AA)
  - 8 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and colleagues during his assignment with the Strategy and Policy Group, 1941-1943; 6 prints of the Wedemeyer home at Ft. Myer, Virginia, circa 1942-1943 (Box 158, Envelope BB)
  - 90 prints of Albert Wedemeyer and colleagues in transit and sightseeing during assignment with the Southeast Asia Command and attendance at the Casablanca Conference, including scenes of Egypt, Paris, and India, 1943-1944 (Box 158, Envelope CC)
  - 33 prints (1 duplicate) of participants at the Casablanca Conference, including Henry H. Arnold, Allen Brooke, Winston Churchill, Charles De Gaulle, Averell Harriman, Ernest King, George Marshall, Louis Mountbatten, George S. Patton, Franklin D. Roosevelt and others, 1943 January (Box 158, Envelope DD)
  - 14 prints of Franklin Roosevelt in French Morocco, Liberia, Brazil, and in transit during his trip to the Casablanca Conference, undated (Box 158, Envelope EE)